Guide to the John Hay Whitney and Betsey Cushing Whitney Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- John Hay Whitney and Betsey Cushing Whitney, 1849-2008; Series I
  - Topical
    - Philanthropy
      - Contributions
        - Whitney, John Hay
          - Political
            - Topical
              - Ripon Society, 1966-1970 (Box 173, Folder 6)
          - Refusals, 1981 (Box 174, Folder 1)
      - Mrs. Payne Whitney Milk Fund
        - Appeals and replies, 1947-1950, 1961 (Box 175, Folder 1)
        - Banking records, 1949-1958 (Box 175, Folder 2-3)
        - Contributors, 1977-1981 (Box 175, Folder 4)
        - Correspondence, general, 1953-1960 (Box 175, Folder 5)
        - Distribution of funds, 1946-1960 (Box 175, Folder 6)
        - Donor lists, 1944-1957 (Box 175, Folder 7)
        - Legal files, 1977-1981 (Box 175, Folder 8)
        - Tax information, annual reports, 1952-1962 (Box 175, Folder 9-10)
      - Northshore Hospital, Thanksgiving Ball, 1951-1957 (Box 176, Folder 1-2)
    - Real estate
      Arranged by property name.
      - 10 Gracie Square, New York, New York, 1955-1956 (Box 176, Folder 3)
      - 25 James's Place, Flat 3, London, United Kingdom, 1967-1997 (Box 176, Folder 4-5)
      - 110 West 51st Street Room 4600, New York, New York
        - Betsey Cushing Whitney office plans (oversize), 1984, undated (Box 394)
        - Renovations, 1984-1985, 1992 (Box 176, Folder 6)
        - Staff, 1948-1953, 1992-1996 (Box 176, Folder 7)
      - 972 5th Avenue, New York, New York
        - Garage plan (oversize), Circa 1910 (Box 394)
        - Venetian Room
          - Appraisal, 1945, 1997, undated (Box 177, Folder 1)
          - Betsey Cushing Whitney estate, 1997-1998 (Box 177, Folder 2-3)
          - Blueprints (oversize), 1948 (Box 394)
          - Deconstruction, 1948-1950, 1997 (Box 177, Folder 4)
          - Deed of gift, 1997 (Box 177, Folder 5)
          - Fabric estimates, 1997-1998 (Box 177, Folder 6)
          - Fabric samples, Circa 1998 (Box 178, Folder 1-4)
          - Furniture estimates, 1998 (Box 179, Folder 1)
          - Restoration brochure, 1998 (Box 179, Folder 2)
        - Whitney family estate, 1945-1996 (Box 179, Folder 3)
      - Beekman Place, Incorporated, New York, New York
        - Alterations
          - General, 1976-1978 (Box 179, Folder 4-5)
          - Floor plans (oversize), 1976 (Box 394)
        - Financial statements, 1977-1997 (Box 179, Folder 6-7)
        - Furnishings, 1976-1978, 1991 (Box 180, Folder 1)
        - Improvements and furnishings, 1977-1978, 1985 (Box 180, Folder 2)
        - Proprietary lease, 1976-1996 (Box 180, Folder 3-4)
        - Shareholders correspondence, 1977-1998 (Box 180, Folder 5-6)
      - East 63rd Street and East 64th Street properties, New York, New York
        Documents the impact of the City Landmarks Commission and the construction of the Third Avenue subway in Manhattan on the Whitney properties in that area.
        - 63rd Street homes, 1957-1958, 1971 (Box 181, Folder 1)
        - 163 East 63rd Street
          - Garden, 1956, 1987 (Box 181, Folder 2)
            Includes drawings and photographs.
          - Furnishings, 1960-1973 (Box 181, Folder 3)
        - 182 East 64th Street, sale to the City of New York, 1984 (Box 181, Folder 4-5)
        - Contract signing, sale of 169 East 63rd Street Corporation and Third Avenue, East 64th Street Corporation, 1983 (Box 181, Folder 6)
        - Correspondence, 1969-1985, 1992 (Box 181, Folder 7-8)
        - Federal income tax returns, 1966-1973 (Box 182, Folder 1)
        - John Hay Whitney real estate services, 169 East 63rd Street Corporation, 64th Street Corporation, 1977-1981 (Box 182, Folder 2)
          Contains information about the changing state of John Hay Whitney's properties on the east side of Manhattan during the Third Avenue subway construction. These reports outline the neighborhood's changing demographics and their impact on Whitney real estate holdings.
        - Property inspections, 1976 (Box 182, Folder 3)
        - Service contracts, 1972-1984 (Box 182, Folder 4-6)
        - Tax assessments, 1969-1975 (Box 182, Folder 7-8)
        - Tenants, 1962-1971 (Box 182, Folder 9)
      - Fishers Island, New York
        - Appraisal, 1982 (Box 183, Folder 1)
        - Blueprints, 1950-1960, 1966 (Box 183, Folder 2-5)
        - Goodwin house, 1953-1954, 1991 (Box 183, Folder 6)
        - Land purchases correspondence, 1948-1962 (Box 183, Folder 7)
        - Land sale, Goodwin house, 1961-1962 (Box 183, Folder 8)
        - Landscaping, 1949-1958 (Box 184, Folder 1-2)
        - Lease correspondence, 1947 (Box 184, Folder 3)
        - Main house inventory, 1966, 1990, 1992 (Box 184, Folder 4-5)
        - Sale
          - Advertising, 1989-1992 (Box 184, Folder 6-7)
          - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 184, Folder 8)
          - Purchase by John G. Brim and Marie Elena A. Brim., 1992 January 29 (Box 185, Folder 1-2)
        - Stamp (wooden), Circa 1950-1970 (Box 185, Folder 3)
      - Greentree, Manhasset, New York
        - Alterations, 1972 (Box 185, Folder 4)
        - Founding Greentree Stables registration certificate, 1911 (Box 185, Folder 5)
        - Museum of Natural History excavation report, 1949-1950 (Box 185, Folder 6)
      - Greenwood, Thomasville, Georgia, appraisal of, 1998, 2007 (Box 185, Folder 7-8)
      - Plandome, Manhasset, New York
        - General, 1926-1928 (Box 185, Folder 9-10)
        - Boathouse blueprint, Circa 1920-1930 (Box 185, Folder 11)
      - Saratoga Springs, New York, New York
        - General, 1982-1998 (Box 186, Folder 1)
        - Elevator, 1980 (Box 186, Folder 2)
        - Fabric samples, Circa 1980-1990 (Box 186, Folder 3)
        - Floor plans, 1987 (Box 186, Folder 4)
        - Press clippings, 1942, 1957, 1977-1981 (Box 186, Folder 5-6)
        - Property appraisal, Circa 1930-1940, circa 1960-1970 (Box 186, Folder 7)
        - Property history
          - General, Circa 1900-1982 (Box 187, Folder 1-2)
          - Commission, 1967 (Box 187, Folder 3)
        - Renovation, 1987 (Box 187, Folder 4-8)
        - Yaddo, abstract of title, Circa 1860-1930 (Box 188, Folder 1)
      - Miscellaneous
        - John Hay Whitney estate properties report, 1982 (Box 188, Folder 2)
        - Payne Whitney memorial blueprint, 1927 (Box 188, Folder 3)
        - United States Trust fees, 1977 (Box 188, Folder 4)
        - Whitney property, offers of purchase, 1971-1975 (Box 188, Folder 5)
  - Biographical
    - Newspaper and magazine clippings
      While the bulk of the clippings pertain to the years John Hay Whitney served as ambassador to the Court of St. James's, most of the major milestones in the lives of John Hay Whitney and Betsey Cushing Whitney are documented, including their first marriages.
      - 1910-1956 (Box 189, Folder 1-15)
        - Oversize (Box 395, Folder 3-5)
      - 1957 (Box 190, Folder 1-7)
        - Oversize (Box 395, Folder 6)
      - 1958-1959 (Box 190, Folder 8-9)
      - 1960-1963 (Box 190, Folder 10-12)
        - Oversize (Box 395, Folder 6)
      - 1964-1967 (Box 190, Folder 13-14)
        - Oversize (Box 395, Folder 7)
      - 1970-1999, undated (Box 191, Folder 1-9)
        - Oversize (Box 395, Folder 8)
    - Whitney, Betsey Cushing
      - General, 1983-1998 (Box 192, Folder 1)
        Includes biographical sketches and her obituary.
      - Awards (oversize), Circa 1970-1990 (Box 396, Folder 2)
      - Cushing family history, 1935-1938, undated (Box 192, Folder 2)
        Includes Harvey Cushing letters to Walter Bett.
      - Daily logs
        - 1991 Sep-1996 (Box 193, Folder 1-8)
        - 1997-1998 Mar (Box 194, Folder 1-3)
      - Datebooks
        - 1948-1951 (Box 195, Folder 1-4)
        - 1952-1954, 1958-1960 (Box 196, Folder 1-6)
        - 1960-1963, 1977-1978 (Box 197, Folder 1-6)
        - 1982-1985 (Box 198, Folder 1-4)
        - 1986-1989 (Box 199, Folder 1-4)
        - 1990-1993 (Box 200, Folder 1-4)
        - 1994-1997 (Box 201, Folder 1-4)
        - 1998 (Box 202, Folder 1)
        - Office copies, 1992-1995 (Box 202, Folder 2-5)
      - Family trees, Circa 1990-1998 (Box 203, Folder 1)
      - Medical records, Circa 1990-1998 (Box 203, Folder 2)
      - Obituaries, 1979, 1997-1998 (Box 203, Folder 3)
      - Office calendars (oversize), 1991-1996 (Box 393, Folder 1-6)
      - Recollections, 1988-1995 (Box 203, Folder 4)
      - Saratoga schedule, 1992-1995 (Box 203, Folder 5-8)
        Includes daily logs of Betsey Cushing Whitney's activities.
    - Whitney, John Hay
      - Awards and certificates, Circa 1935-1965 (Box 203, Folder 9)
        - Oversize (Box 396, Folder 1)
      - Biographies
        - General, 1926, 1940-1993 (Box 204, Folder 1-2)
        - Correspondence, 1940-1982 (Box 204, Folder 3)
        - Kahn biography, Jock: The Life and Times of John Hay Whitney
          - Comments, 1980-1981 (Box 204, Folder 4)
          - Correspondence, 1978-1983 (Box 204, Folder 5)
          - Research, 1979-1981 (Box 204, Folder 6)
        - Paley Foundation biography, 1986 (Box 204, Folder 7)
      - Birth and baptismal certificates, passports, 1905-1982 (Box 204, Folder 8)
      - Datebooks
        - 1948-1955 (Box 205, Folder 1-15)
        - 1956-1962 (Box 206, Folder 1-16)
        - 1963-1970 (Box 207, Folder 1-12)
        - 1971-1982 (Box 208, Folder 1-12)
      - Family trees, Circa 1940-1990 (Box 209, Folder 1)
      - Guestbook, Expediter (John Hay Whitney's plane), 1957 (Box 209, Folder 2)
      - Groton School
        - Class book, 1918 (Box 209, Folder 3)
        - Exams, Circa 1918-1922 (Box 209, Folder 4)
        - Notebooks, Circa 1918-1922 (Box 209, Folder 5-6)
      - Military service records
        - General, 1941-1965 (Box 209, Folder 7)
        - Army Air Force 201, 1941-1945 (Box 210, Folder 1-3)
        - Escape story, 1945 (Box 210, Folder 4-5)
          Includes handwritten annotations by John Hay Whitney.
      - Obituaries, 1979, 1982 (Box 210, Folder 6)
      - "People, Places, and Things," index of, Circa 1978 (Box 210, Folder 7)
      - Speeches
        General
        For speeches as ambassador, see Ambassadorial files--Speeches.
        - Speeches 1963-1964 (list) (Box 211, Folder 1)
        - American Association of Advertising Agencies, 1961 April 21 (Box 211, Folder 2)
        - Art and the Americas, 1941 April 14 (Box 211, Folder 3)
        - Churchill, Winston, memorial service, 1965 January 31 (Box 211, Folder 4)
        - Connecticut Daily Newspaper Association, 1961 September 28 (Box 211, Folder 5)
        - Dedication of Bennet-Greely plaque, 1963 October 16 (Box 211, Folder 6)
        - Empire Club of Canada, 1963 December 5 (Box 211, Folder 7)
        - English Speaking Union, 1962 June 1, November 14 (Box 211, Folder 8)
        - Franklin Institute, 1963 May 7 (Box 211, Folder 9)
        - Freedom is our Business, 1951-1952 (Box 211, Folder 10-11)
        - Fund for Medical Progress, 1965 May 11 (Box 211, Folder 12)
        - Groton School Alumni Association, 1961 April 12 (Box 212, Folder 1)
        - Guion Building, 1963 May 8 and 18 (Box 212, Folder 2)
        - John Hay Fellows, 1961 May 6 (Box 212, Folder 3)
        - Lord and Taylor, 1941 April 29 (Box 212, Folder 4)
        - The Lost Question, 1953 (Box 212, Folder 5-6)
        - Lovejoy address, 1964 (Box 212, Folder 7-9)
        - The Meaning of Modern Capitalism, 1956 May 17 (Box 213, Folder 1)
        - Modern Venture Capitalism, 1955 (Box 213, Folder 2)
        - The Museum's Place in National Defense, 1941 June 16 (Box 213, Folder 3)
        - National Newspaper Association, 1961 May 22 (Box 213, Folder 4)
        - Neiman Foundation Dinner speech, 1963 November 26 (Box 213, Folder 5)
        - New York Herald Tribune
          - 25 Year Club Luncheon, 1964 April 7 (Box 213, Folder 6)
          - Forum, 1961 March 24 (Box 213, Folder 7)
          - World Youth Forum
            - 1963 Mar 21 (Box 213, Folder 8)
            - 1964 Mar 19 (Box 213, Folder 9)
            - 1965 Mar 25 (Box 213, Folder 10)
            - 1966 Mar 31 (Box 213, Folder 11)
        - Producers Association, 1940 (Box 213, Folder 12)
        - Protestant Council Family of Men award honoring Dwight D. Eisenhower, 1964 (Box 213, Folder 13-14)
        - Publishers Lunch Club, 1965 March 4 (Box 214, Folder 1)
        - The Right to Think, 1954 June 14 (Box 214, Folder 2-3)
        - Tax Foundation dinner, 1964 December 1 (Box 214, Folder 4)
        - Thoroughbred Club of America, 1963 October 17 (Box 214, Folder 5)
        - Yale Corporation Dinner, 1973 May 11 (Box 214, Folder 6)
        - Young Women's Christian Association, 1962 October 17 (Box 214, Folder 7)
        - Miscellaneous, 1937-1941, 1961-1965, 1973 (Box 214, Folder 8)
      - St. Bernard's School, examination records, 1914-1918 (Box 214, Folder 9)
      - Travel
        Includes agendas, itineraries, and background information on locations.
        - General (list of trips), Undated (Box 215, Folder 1)
        - Georgia, Virginia, 1961 (Box 215, Folder 2)
        - Germany, 1961 (Box 215, Folder 3)
        - Korea
          Includes correspondence about John Hay Whitney's role as special ambassador to the inauguration of President Syngman Rhee.
          - General, 1956 (Box 215, Folder 4-7)
          - Photograph albums, 1956, 1958 (Box 215, Folder 8-9)
        - London, 1965 (Box 215, Folder 10)
        - London, Paris, 1961-1966 (Box 215, Folder 11-15)
        - New Haven, Connecticut, 1963-1964 (Box 215, Folder 16)
        - Paris, London, 1962-1964 (Box 215, Folder 17-19)
        - San Francisco, California, 1964 (Box 215, Folder 20)
        - Washington, D.C., 1961-1965 (Box 215, Folder 21-23)
      - Yale University notebook, Circa 1922-1926 (Box 216, Folder 1)
- Payne and Helen Hay Whitney Family, 1826-1988; Series II
  The series is arranged alphabetically by name.
  Largely comprised of correspondence between 1880 and 1920, the series documents Helen Hay and Payne Whitney and immediate family members. The bulk of the series is related to Helen Hay, particularly her literary career. There are letters she received about her published writings, as well as letters exchanged with other writers about their own writing, in which they solicited her counsel. There are also examples of her writings from the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries. Payne Whitney's files provide only partial documentation of his multifaceted personal and professional lives. The limited correspondence of John M. Hay is largely focused on personal matters; the majority of his papers are at Brown University.
  - Clippings, 1880-1929 (Box 217, Folder 1-11)
    - Oversize (Box 395, Folder 1-2)
  - Hay, John M.
    - Biographical files, Circa 1910 (Box 218, Folder 1)
    - Certificates, Circa 1890s (Box 218, Folder 2)
      - Oversize (Box 397, Folder 1)
    - Collection of John Hay Materials, 1863-1904, undated (Box 218, Folder 3)
      Portfolio containing correspondence, photographs, and memorabilia.
    - Correspondence
      - Alphabetical
        - Birth of Joan Whitney Payson, 1903 (Box 218, Folder 4)
        - Bondy, M., 1899 (Box 218, Folder 5)
        - Family members, 1880-1900 (Box 218, Folder 6)
        - Kipling, Rudyard, Circa 1895 (Box 218, Folder 7-8)
        - Lincoln assassination, 1893 (Box 218, Folder 9)
        - Literary activities, 1870, 1876 (Box 218, Folder 10)
        - Lowell, James Russell, 1882-1886 (Box 218, Folder 11)
        - Raymond, S. A., 1890-1900 (Box 218, Folder 12)
        - Roosevelt, Theodore, Circa 1903 (Box 218, Folder 13)
        - Whitney, Helen Hay, Circa 1890-1900 (Box 218, Folder 14)
      - Chronological
        - 1861-1889 (Box 219, Folder 1-27)
        - 1890-1905, undated (Box 220, Folder 1-18)
    - Finances, Circa 1870-1900 (Box 220, Folder 19)
    - Funeral program, 1905 (Box 220, Folder 20)
    - Gladstone, William, funeral files, 1898 (Box 221, Folder 1)
    - Hay, Aldebert, (Helen Hay's brother) memorial for, Circa 1901 (Box 221, Folder 2)
    - John Hay National Wildlife Refuge Landscape history, 1988 (Box 221, Folder 3)
      - Oversize (Box 397, Folder 2)
    - King, Clarence, thoughts on, Circa 1900s (Box 221, Folder 4)
    - Legal, 1826-1871 (Box 221, Folder 5)
    - Lincoln, Abraham, biography press files, 1886-1887 (Box 221, Folder 6)
    - Message of the President of the United States, 1904 (Box 221, Folder 7)
    - Poetry, Circa 1880-1900 (Box 221, Folder 8)
    - Political writings, Circa 1890s (Box 221, Folder 9)
    - Politics, Circa 1890-1900 (Box 221, Folder 10)
    - Seating charts, 1887-1889, undated (Box 221, Folder 11)
      Charts reflect the social network of the Hay family during John M. Hay's service in Washington, D. C.
    - Will and estate files, Circa 1900-1905 (Box 221, Folder 12)
  - Payson, Joan Whitney
    - Baby book, 1903-1904 (Box 221, Folder 13)
    - Biographical, 1948-1975 (Box 221, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence
      - Friends, 1924 (Box 221, Folder 15)
      - Whitney, John Hay, 1917-1921 (Box 221, Folder 16)
    - Helen Hay Foundation, 1966-1984 (Box 222, Folder 1-2)
    - The Wheel magazine, 1919 (Box 222, Folder 3)
  - Whitney, Helen Hay
    - Art, 1930 (Box 222, Folder 4)
    - Book lists, 1900-1930 (Box 222, Folder 5)
    - Certificates, 1918-1933 (Box 222, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence
      - Adams, Henry, 1901-1908 (Box 222, Folder 7)
      - Birth of Joan Whitney Payson (daughter), 1903 (Box 222, Folder 8)
      - Birth of John Hay Whitney (son), 1904 (Box 222, Folder 9)
      - Brown University, 1906-1910 (Box 222, Folder 10)
        Includes information about the dedication of the John Hay Library.
      - Calling cards, Circa 1890-1940 (Box 223)
      - Darrell, Parke, 1900-1901 (Box 224, Folder 1)
      - Death of Aldebert Hay (brother), 1901 (Box 224, Folder 2-15)
      - Death of Clara Stone Hay (mother), 1914 (Box 225, Folder 1)
      - Death of John M. Hay (father), 1905 (Box 225, Folder 2-5)
      - Death of Payne Whitney, 1927 (Box 225, Folder 6)
      - Engagement to Payne Whitney
        - Correspondence, 1901 (Box 225, Folder 7-9)
        - Correspondence (continued), 1901 (Box 226, Folder 1-6)
      - Family, general, 1895, 1900-1901, 1927, 1932 (Box 227, Folder 1)
      - Friends, general
        - 1892, 1894-1897 (Box 227, Folder 2-6)
        - 1898-1903 (Box 228, Folder 1-8)
        - 1904-1937 (Box 229, Folder 1-25)
        - Undated (Box 230, Folder 1-5)
      - Graham, Harry, 1899-1905 (Box 231, Folder 1-3)
      - Gray, David, 1898 (Box 231, Folder 4)
      - Guise, Arthur, 1900-1910 (Box 231, Folder 5)
      - Hay, Clara Stone (mother)
        - Circa 1890-1900 (Box 232, Folder 1-7)
        - 1892, 1900-1902 (Box 233, Folder 1-5)
        - 1903-1905 (Box 234, Folder 1-6)
        - 1906-1912 (Box 235, Folder 1-9)
      - Hay, Clarence (brother), 1903-1905 (Box 236, Folder 1-2)
      - Hay, John M. (father)
        - General, 1891-1905 (Box 236, Folder 3-9)
        - Writings, 1921,1937 (Box 236, Folder 10)
      - Horses and racing, 1917, 1932 (Box 236, Folder 11)
      - Invitations, Circa 1900-1915 (Box 236, Folder 12-13)
      - Laurier, Pamela, 1901-1909 (Box 237, Folder 1-2)
      - Ledyard, Lewis Cass, 1932 (Box 237, Folder 3)
      - Literary expertise, 1933 (Box 237, Folder 4)
      - Lodge, Constance, Circa 1890s (Box 237, Folder 5)
      - Lodge, George Cabot
        - Circa 1890-1900 (Box 238, Folder 1-3)
        - 1892-1893 (Box 238, Folder 4)
        - 1894-1900 (Box 239, Folder 1-5)
      - Marquay, George, 1901-1909 (Box 240, Folder 1-2)
      - Milk Fair, 1933-1936 (Box 240, Folder 3)
      - New York Hospital, 1932 (Box 240, Folder 4)
      - Paget, Pauline, 1901-1902 (Box 240, Folder 5)
      - Payne, Oliver Hazard (uncle to Payne Whitney), 1902-1903 (Box 240, Folder 6)
      - Payson, Daniel, 1932 (Box 240, Folder 7)
      - Payson, Joan Whitney (daughter), Circa 1910-1930 (Box 240, Folder 8-9)
      - Payson, Sandra, 1936 (Box 240, Folder 10)
      - Peabody, Endicott, 1922 (Box 240, Folder 11)
      - Poetry, 1898 (Box 240, Folder 12)
      - Poetry by others, Circa 1890-1910 (Box 240, Folder 13)
      - Poetry set to music, Circa 1900 (Box 240, Folder 14)
      - Published works, Circa 1900-1910 (Box 240, Folder 15)
      - Publishers, 1895-1907, 1930 (Box 241, Folder 1-2)
      - Rollins, F.S., 1932 (Box 241, Folder 3)
      - Staff, 1878-1935 (Box 241, Folder 4)
      - Vannah, Kate, Circa 1900s (Box 241, Folder 5)
      - Wadsworth, Alice Hay, Circa 1890, 1900-1909, circa 1930 (Box 241, Folder 6-10)
      - Wadsworth, James, Jr., Circa 1891-1901 (Box 242, Folder 1)
      - Whitney, Alice Appleton, Circa 1900s (Box 242, Folder 2)
      - Whitney, Gertrude Vanderbilt (sister-in-law), 1903-1905, undated (Box 242, Folder 3)
      - Whitney, John Hay (son), 1912, 1918-1933 (Box 242, Folder 4-5)
      - Whitney, Payne (husband)
        The letters provide insight into Helen Hay Whitney and Payne Whitney's courtship, friendship, and expectations of marriage.
        - 1898 Jan-1901 May (Box 243, Folder 1-7)
        - 1901 Jun-Oct (Box 244, Folder 1-6)
        - 1901 Nov-1911 (Box 245, Folder 1-8)
        - Undated (Box 246, Folder 1-2)
      - Whitney, William Collins (father-in-law), 1902 (Box 246, Folder 3)
      - Wilder, Thornton, 1932 (Box 246, Folder 4)
      - Writing requests, Circa 1900-1915 (Box 246, Folder 5)
      - Writings, Circa 1900 (Box 246, Folder 6)
      - Writings by others, 1900-1902, undated (Box 246, Folder 7)
      - Yale University, 1931-1932 (Box 246, Folder 8)
    - Gift book, Circa 1910-1920 (Box 246, Folder 9)
    - Gift receipts, 1916, 1930 (Box 246, Folder 10)
    - Guestbook, Circa 1910-1920 (Box 246, Folder 11)
    - Passports, 1921-1929 (Box 246, Folder 12)
    - Royalty statements, 1907 (Box 246, Folder 13)
    - Social engagements, Circa 1890-1900 (Box 246, Folder 14)
    - Stock certificates, 1903 (Box 246, Folder 15)
    - Thoroughbreds: Property of Greentree Stable, 1931 (Box 246, Folder 16)
    - Writing contracts, 1901, 1905 (Box 246, Folder 17)
    - Writings by
      - Type of material
        - Drafts, Circa 1890-1910 (Box 246, Folder 18)
        - Notebooks, Circa 1890-1927 (Box 247, Folder 1-5)
      - Title
        - "30", Circa 1900-1910 (Box 247, Folder 6)
        - Beasts and Birds, 1900 (Box 398, Folder 4)
        - The Bed-Time Book, 1907 (Box 398, Folder 4)
        - "Boy o" Dreams" song, verse by Helen hay Whitney, music by Charles Bochau, Circa 1900 (Box 398, Folder 3)
        - "The Budget", 1916 (Box 247, Folder 7)
        - "Dulce Dulce", Circa 1900-1910 (Box 247, Folder 8)
        - "The Flowers of Proscepine", Circa 1900-1910 (Box 247, Folder 9)
        - "Free", Circa 1900-1910 (Box 247, Folder 10)
        - "The Ghost Dance", Circa 1900-1910 (Box 247, Folder 11)
        - Gypsy Verses, comments and sheet music, 1907 (Box 247, Folder 12)
        - "Isolt the Desirious", Circa 1900-1910 (Box 247, Folder 13)
        - The Little Boy Book, 1900 (Box 398, Folder 1)
        - "Magnolia", Circa 1900-1910 (Box 247, Folder 14)
        - "The Reversion", Circa 1900-1910 (Box 247, Folder 15)
        - The Rose of Dawn draft, 1901 (Box 247, Folder 16)
        - "The Seven Silent Ones", Circa 1900-1910 (Box 247, Folder 17)
        - "Shadows", Circa 1900-1910 (Box 247, Folder 18)
        - Some Verses, comments, 1898 (Box 247, Folder 19)
        - "Sonnet", Circa 1900-1910 (Box 247, Folder 20)
        - "Three Songs" by Blair Fairchild, words by Helen Hay Whitney, 1907 (Box 398, Folder 3)
        - Verses for Jock and Joan, 1905 (Box 398, Folder 2)
        - "A Visit to the Menagerie", Circa 1900-1910 (Box 247, Folder 21)
        - "Visitors" song, words by Helen Hay Whitney, music by Waddington Cooke, 1905 (Box 398, Folder 3)
        - Miscellaneous, Circa 1900-1910 (Box 248, Folder 1-2)
    - Writings by others, Circa 1900-1910 (Box 248, Folder 3)